As of **15 DEC 2021** and **30 DEC 22** this privacy policy is combined with the previously separate cookies policy and now defunct Terms of Service policy.

avoidthehack Privacy Policy
===========================

This privacy policy was last updated: **19 MAR 2024** Previous versions of the privacy policy are [available on GitHub](https://github.com/avoidthehack/privacy-policy).

As a website that promotes end-user cybersecurity and privacy, avoidthehack! respects the privacy of all visitors. As a testament to this, this privacy policy will be short and easy to understand.

Information collected
---------------------

avoidthehack (which includes web properties owned by avoidthehack) uses [Umami for analytics](https://umami.is/), which is an open-source and privacy-friendly analytics software. It is GDPR and CCPA compliant.

Umami is hosted on cloud server infrastructure provided by Vultr, so the limited information it captures is only available for website administrator use. avoidthehack's instance of Umami collects:

* User-agent string
* The pages of this website (and only this website) that you visit
* Your browser's referrer header, _if_ one is sent. This is automatically anonymized so only the domain of the URL is collected, even if your browser offers the full string.

The Umami analytics software does not store cookies on your device or log IP addresses. If your browser happens to send a "do not track" (DNT) request to the avoidthehack website on your behalf, these requests are honored by default.

avoidthehack doesn't collect personally identifiable information without consent from the user.

How avoidthehack uses your information
--------------------------------------

**avoidthehack! DOES NOT sell any personal information... because there's nothing to sell.**

The information avoidthehack collects via Umami is used to further improve avoidthehack for all visitors. Information collected is used to:

* Optimize this website for speed and ease-of-use
* Ensure site security from potential attackers
* Understand traffic volume (hits per page)

### Your email address

**Contact:** If you reach out to the general inbox on the contact page, then your email address will be used to respond to your message.

Users wanting to remain anonymous when contacting avoidthehack are encouraged to use an alias or a temporary email address to do so. Also, you can reach out via social media platforms where avoidthehack has an account.

**Post comments:** If you choose to authenticate to the comment section via social login, your email address is also shared with avoidthehack. This email address is only used to uniquely identify you when commenting (it is not displayed to the public) and is stored for as long as you grant permission via your social login settings.

Note that it is possible to comment on posts anonymously without sharing your email address.

**Newsletter:** If you opt-in to the newsletter, _Updates From Avoid the Hack_, your provided email address will be used to receive the newsletter. Note that the newsletter service is hosted at [Buttondown](https://buttondown.email/legal/privacy), which leaves you subject to their privacy policy as well. Users are welcomed to use alias/masked email addresses to opt-in. Account creation is not required.

**Note:** Email addresses provided are **not used** outside of their intended purposes. For example, if you use a social login to authenticate to the comment section, the shared email from this is not used for anything else.

Cookies from avoidthehack!
--------------------------

avoidthehack _does not_ use third-party cookies. avoidthehack! uses **session cookies** and **persistent cookies.**

### Session cookies

A session cookie is used to identify a particular visit to avoidthehack!. The session cookie is set to expire after 30 minutes, or after you close your web browser after visiting avoidthehack.

These cookies are used to identify you during a single browsing session and do not store personally identifiable information.

### Persistent cookies

A persistent cookie may be stored on your device if you use social logins to authenticate to the comment section on posts.

Updates From Avoid the Hack!

No [spam](https://avoidthehack.com/privacy-policy). Must confirm email. Unsubscribe anytime. [View archive](https://buttondown.email/avoidthehack) for a sneak peak!

###### Information

###### Privacy+Cybersecurity

###### Other

© 2020 - 2024 avoidthehack! LLC
